hotornot.com 2015-12-04

# Hot or Not's Privacy Policy

This policy and any dispute or claim arising out of or in connection with it or its subject matter (including non-contractual disputes or claims) shall be governed by and construed in accordance with English law. In the event there is a discrepancy between this English language version and any translated copies of the Privacy Policy, the English version shall prevail. 

## What’s this all about then?

Hello (again, if you clicked through to here from our [Terms and Conditions of Use](http://hotornot.com/terms/)). You should read this privacy policy because it will tell you exactly how your personal data is being looked after by Hot or Not and that’s a pretty important thing for you to know. Here are the topics that we cover: 

  1. What information we collect and how we collect it
  2. How we use the information and who we share it with
  3. How you can access and update such information
  4. How we protect the information we store about you

## Who we are

Hot or Not is operated by Or Not Limited, a company registered in England at Media Village, 131 - 151 Great Titchfield Street, London, W1W 5BB, United Kingdom and company number 07976476. 

## The full legal bit

We know that other people’s use of your personal data is a big concern for social network users, so we at Hot or Not have developed this privacy policy (the “ **Policy** ”) to let you know how we use personal information (‘personal data’ or ‘personal information’). 

Our Policy applies to your use of the Hot or Not app and website at http://hotornot.com/ (“Hot or Not”). We suggest you read it in conjunction with our [Terms and Conditions of Use](http://hotornot.com/terms/) (the “ **Terms** ”). When you access or use Hot or Not, you agree to our Privacy Policy and you consent to our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as we’ve set out in this Policy. 

Hot or Not reserves the right to change our Policy at any time and without notice, so be sure to check this Policy regularly to understand how we use your information. 

IF YOU DO NOT ACCEPT AND AGREE WITH OUR PRIVACY POLICY THEN YOU MUST NOT ACCESS OR USE THE APP OR SITE. 

## 1. Hot or Not users and visitors to our site

#### What information does Hot or Not collect if I decide to join the Hot or Not social community?

Hot or Not is a place for meeting new people, and we provide that service by operating a social network app and site offering users the opportunity to connect to our global community of users. 

To join the Hot or Not network we have several ways you can sign in. You may be able to sign in with your email address, and you will provide us with your full name, your gender, your date of birth, and your location details, which we will collect. You can also sign in with your Facebook profile, from which we will collect your full name, your gender, your date of birth, your location details, your profile photos, your list of public friends, and your interests. 

Other ways to join the Hot or Not network are by signing in with your Google Plus profile, from which we will collect your basic profile info, such as your full name, your gender, your list of friends in your circle and your email address. You can also join via other social networks available in certain countries from which we will collect your full name, your gender, your friends, your date of birth, your email address and your location details. 

You may also have the opportunity to provide other details about yourself, but these are optional. Because you control your user profile, these details are available to you at any time by accessing your “Profile” page, which gives you the chance to correct or update your information (other than gender and your date of birth) at any time by just logging in to Hot or Not. We may require you to verify your Profile and provide us with a phone number for the sole purpose of verification. We will take measures to keep this safe in accordance with this policy. 

Once you have created a Profile, we will automatically track certain information such as your IP and email addresses, (if you have provided this to us). 

#### What information does Hot or Not collect about me if I’m under 13? 

You can only become a member of Hot or Not if you are aged 13 or over. That means Hot or Not does not knowingly collect any information about anyone under the age of 13. Nor do we knowingly market to anyone under the age of 13. If you are less than 13 years old, we request that you do not submit information to us. If we become aware that anyone under the age of 13 has registered with us and provided us with personal information, we will take steps to terminate that person’s registration and delete their Profile information from Hot or Not. If we do delete a Profile because you violated our no under 13 rules, we may retain your email and IP address to ensure that you do not try to get around our rules by creating a new Profile. 

#### Does Hot or Not collect my personal information if I am not a member and just visit the site? 

No. We don’t collect any personal information about visitors to our site. If you do visit us without becoming a member, we will place session ID cookies on your mobile or computer. For more information about cookies generally, look at the answer to _“How does Hot or Not collect information about me?”_ below. 

#### If I put other information about me on the app or site, what does Hot or Not do with it? 

Hot or Not is designed to make it easy for you to find, connect and interact with other members of Hot or Not by posting information about yourself. You can also use our electronic messaging system, which allows you to communicate with other users. We recommend and encourage you (and all our members) to think carefully about the information they disclose about themselves. We also do not recommend that you put email addresses, URLs, instant messaging details, phone numbers, full names or addresses, credit card details, national identity numbers, drivers’ licence details and other sensitive information in your Profile which is open to abuse and misuse. 

Please be careful about posting sensitive details about yourself on your Profile such as your religious denomination and health details. While you may voluntarily provide this information to us when you create your Profile, including your sexual preferences and ethnic background, there is no requirement to do so. Please remember that photographs that you post on Hot or Not may reveal this kind of sensitive personal data. Where you do upload and choose to tell us sensitive information about yourself, you are explicitly consenting to our processing your information and making this public to other users. 

If you are between the ages of 13- 17 years of age, we are afraid you cannot chat or share photos with anyone outside of that age bracket. If you are 18 years old or over, we do not permit you to start new conversations or share photos with anyone younger than 18.

When you post information about yourself or use the messaging, the amount of personal information you share is at your own risk. If you post anything that is inconsistent with our [Terms and Conditions of Use](http://hotornot.com/terms/), we reserve the right to terminate your account. 

#### What does Hot or Not collect about me if I use the mobile app? 

Hot or Not offers you the opportunity to stay in touch with the friends and contacts you’ve made no matter where you are. You can do this by using your mobile phone. 

When you use your mobile app, we will collect information about WiFi access points as well as other location information about your longitude and latitude. That information helps us identify your physical location so that it can be displayed and shared with other members choosing to view “nearby” posts. 

We use third parties such as Foursquare to provide data on which the location information on Hot or Not is based. When doing so, we receive and use data of Foursquare's users, and we share data with Foursquare for use by Foursquare for its own purposes. For more information on how Foursquare treat data, please see <https://foursquare.com/legal/privacy/>

#### Can Hot or Not collect information about me from other sites I use, such as Facebook? 

If you have joined our network through another social network, such as Facebook, or Google+, parts of your social network profile (such as your interest, profile photos and name) will be available to all users of the Hot or Not social network. 

Remember that when you register with Facebook or any other social network, you are also giving them personal information, so we recommend that you read their privacy policies as Hot or Not does not control how they use their information. 

If you use the voting feature on Hot or Not, you can share these voting results on celebrities and other Hot or Not users on other social networks. You can turn this sharing feature off in your settings at any time. 

Once you have registered through Facebook or another social network, we will connect your Hot or Not profile with that social network profile. We may do this by way of new products and applications, which we, or one of our partners‘ introduce from time to time.

If you have created a Hot or Not profile through Facebook or another social network, and you do not want to link your Hot or Not profile to your profile on Facebook or other social network, Hot or Not cannot amend these settings. Please visit the application settings on your Facebook or other social network profile and follow the instructions to remove the Hot or Not access permissions. 

#### Does Hot or Not collect any other personal information about me? 

If you contact our Customer Support team we will receive your email address, and may track your IP address as well as the information you send to us to help resolve your query. We will keep records of our communications with you, including any complaints that we receive from you about other users (and from other users about you). 

#### Will Hot or Not contact me? 

On your “ **Settings** ” page Hot or Not offers you the opportunity to receive emails from us about new message notifications or other purposes related to the use of the website or app. 

#### Does Hot or Not use my personal information for any other purpose? 

We may use material that you post on the open access areas of Hot or Not in advertising and promotional materials on our partner sites and partner products. We believe these uses allow us to improve our app or website and better tailor your online experience to meet your needs. 

We use your personal information to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our [Terms and Conditions of Use](http://hotornot.com/terms/).

#### What are 'cookies' and what 'cookies' does Hot or Not use? 

We collect information by placing cookies on your computer or mobile. A cookie is a piece of text stored on your computer or mobile by your web browser. They are basically a tool that stores information about website visits, recognises you and your preferences each time you visit Hot or Not, and ensures site functionality and enables us to provide the services our members request. 

When you visit the publicly available sections of Hot or Not, a session ID cookie is placed on your computer that only lasts while you’re visiting. We also place persistent cookies (also known an local storage devices) on members’ computers, so that Hot or Not remembers them and makes their login experience faster and easier. We may use persistent tracking cookies on your mobile device, mainly for security protection purposes, such as to prevent phishers, scammers, unauthorised log-in attempts, and to help you regain access if your account is hacked. We do not use any information whilst you are logged off. 

You may set your browser and your mobile settings to block cookies and local storage devices, but if you do so, you may not be able to access the features that Hot or Not offers. 

Hot or Not uses cookies and local storage devices for a number of reasons, including to ensure the security of our app and site, to provide you with features you have requested and to analyse how members and visitors use Hot or Not. Hot or Not’s use of cookies and local storage devices basically falls into three categories: 

  * those that are strictly necessary to deliver the services and products you have requested. 
  * cookies related to the performance of Hot or Not’s app or site, such as analytics that help us determine how our app or site is performing and ensuring a smooth and trouble free experience for our members and visitors
  * cookies related to the functionality of Hot or Not’s app or site, such as remembering your preferences at log in or your preferred language or allowing you to chat, add photos and instant message Hot or Not members
  * third parties cookies that also relate to functionality and that you request via social plugins, links to other social networks or viewing of videos

Hot or Not’s uses of cookies and local shared devices so that we know who you are, what interests you and so that you can do the things online that you want to do, like chat with new people and share your content knowing that your data will be secure. Below is a table to explain Hot or Not’s cookie functions and why they’re used. 

Cookie Functions | Cookie Purposes  
---|---  
Analytics and research | Hot or Not uses Google Analytics to collect information about how visitors use the Hot or Not app or website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the app or site, where visitors have come to the app or site from and the pages they visited. For more information about Google’s privacy policy, please visit <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/>  
Authentication | These cookies help us to identify our members so that when you’re logged in, you can enjoy Hot or Not’s offerings, experiences and various features, such as uploading photographs, chatting and can localise your experience, such as when you’ve requested to view Hot or Not’s app or site in your local language or when you’ve asked Hot or Not to ‘remember me’. These cookies also help to remember who invited you to join Hot or Not.  
Security and site integrity | 

We use cookies and other devices, such as CAPTCHAs, to help keep Hot or Not and our members safe and secure. These cookies do things like protect Hot or Not users from spam and fraud, by ensuring the safety of your personal data when you shop on Hot or Not.

We may use persistent cookies, which will help us to ensure we have identified the same device is logging into the correct account. These types of cookies also help with our anti-spam measures and may help us to prevent phishers, scammers, unauthorised log -in attempts to your account and accessing any hacked accounts.  
  
Site features and services | 

These cookies and local storage devices provide the functionality that our Hot or Not members enjoy, such as uploading of photographs, chats, instant messaging, your account settings and your request to have Hot or Not as your homepage or your search preference. We also use cookies to help provide experiences, such as links to other social media sites, social plugins and video content, including making it easier for you to share content between Hot or Not with your other favourite social networks.

In some cases, the app or site feature you choose may allow a third party to place cookies or save data to your local storage devices on your computer. The third party who places cookies on your device is responsible for how they process their data and Hot or Not recommends that you read their privacy policies. Third parties who place cookies on your device when you use Hot or Not include, and we have included a link to their privacy policies:

Twitter, <https://twitter.com/privacy> Facebook, <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other#socialplugin> YouTube, <http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy/> AddThis, <http://www.addthis.com/privacy>  
  
Performance | We need to use certain cookies and save data to your local storage devices to ensure our members have the best possible experience, such assisting with your navigation of our app and site, ensuring pages load up quickly and respond faster to your requests for Hot or Not services.  
  
Our use of cookies and local storage devices, including the specific cookie names, may change over time, but will generally fall into the above categories. Please visit this page regularly so that you are aware of any changes.

If you would like to know more about cookies, including flash cookies/local storage devices, the following websites provide useful information:

  * <http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html>

For a video about cookies visit [www.google.co.uk/goodtoknow/data-on-the-web/cookies](http://www.google.co.uk/goodtoknow/data-on-the-web/cookies)

## 2. Friends and other Hot or Not users

#### When I put information about myself on Hot or Not, what do the other users see? 

To ensure you get to meet as many people as possible on Hot or Not, other members may get to see your user name, full name, and any information you post on your Profile, including photos. Any information you choose to provide should reflect how much you want other Hot or Not members to know about you. 

#### What am I allowed to do with other user’s personal information? 

Use it to meet new friends and make new contacts! Beware that you may not use other users' information for commercial purposes, to spam, to harass, or to make unlawful threats. Hot or Not reserves the right to terminate the accounts of those who misuse other users' information or who otherwise violate the [Terms and Conditions of Use](http://hotornot.com/terms/).

## 3. Third parties

#### Does Hot or Not sell my information to other parties? 

Not at all. We do not sell or rent out any personal information about you to any third party. Hot or Not discloses aggregated non-personal data for marketing and promotional purposes. That means we do not disclose any information that could be used to identify you. 

#### Does Hot or Not disclose my information to other parties? 

We may share aggregated information with such parties as Foursquare that includes your personal information (but which doesn’t identify you directly), together with other information including log data with third parties for industry analysis and demographic profiling and to deliver targeted advertising about other products and services. 

In particular, in relation to targeted advertising, we may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our app or website. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other apps and websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please visit [this page](http://networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

If you choose to, we may share your information with vendors, service providers, and other carefully selected third parties to improve our services to you, such as by facilitating payments. We ensure these parties must adhere to strict data protection and confidentiality provisions that are consistent with this Privacy Policy.

Hot or Not also wishes to maintain a healthy community, and we will cooperate with all law enforcement inquiries and with all third parties to enforce their intellectual property or other rights. We may also disclose your personal information to government or law enforcement agencies, or private parties, as required by law when/or, in our sole discretion, we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our legal rights, or those of third parties and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us. 

In the event that Hot or Not or any of its affiliates undergoes a business transition or change of ownership, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, re-organisation, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, or in the event of insolvency or administration, we may be required to disclose your personal information. 

## 4. Data storage

#### Where is my personal information kept? 

Hot or Not is a global app and website operating through servers located in a number of countries around the world, including the United States. If you live in a country with data protection laws, the storage of your personal data may not provide you with the same protections as you enjoy in your country of residence. By submitting your personal information, or by choosing to upgrade the services you use, or by making use of the applications available on Hot or Not, you agree to the transfer of your personal information to, and storage and processing of your personal information in, any such countries and destinations. 

## 5. Security

#### How does Hot or Not protect my personal information? 

Hot or Not has implemented reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect and prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control, including your personal information. Hot or Not uses reasonable security measures to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information such as secured servers using firewalls. Our technical experts at Hot or Not work hard to ensure your secure use of our site. 

While we take reasonable precautions against possible security breaches of our app, website, member database and records no app, website or Internet transmission is completely secure and we cannot guarantee that unauthorised access, hacking, data loss, or other breaches will never occur. We urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe (including your Facebook details) and to log out of your account after use. 

We cannot guarantee the security of your personal data while it is being transmitted to our app or site and any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information we have procedures and security features in place to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

#### How do I help keep my information secure? 

You may not disclose your login details to any third parties or share it with any third parties. If you lose your login details or give them out, your personal information may be compromised. If that happens, you must change your login details immediately. Hot or Not cannot be held responsible for your failure to keep your login details secure and failure to do so may violate our [Terms and Conditions of Use](http://hotornot.com/terms/).

## 6. Your rights

#### How do I change my Profile? 

You can review and revise your profile information at any time. Once you register, you will be able to review and change much of your personal information through your Facebook profile and, for some features, through your Settings page including your profile and photographs. Please promptly update your information if it changes by signing-in to your account and following the screen prompts. We strongly urge you to periodically change your password to help reduce the risk of unauthorised access to your account information. 

Users in certain jurisdictions are, in accordance with applicable law, entitled to exercise a right of access to personal information about themselves by asking for a copy of the information we hold about them (for which, where allowed by law, we may charge a small fee). Please put any such request in writing and using our contact form on our website.

#### Can I deactivate or delete my Profile? 

Users of the Hot or Not network may delete their profile from our database: 

  1. Sign into your account, go to the 'Account' option in your settings and delete your profile. 

If you want to stop using your account it will be initially deactivated. This means that no user will be able to search for you on the app or website although they may still see your profile from direct cached links, but it will not be deleted. We save your profile information in case you later decide to restore your account. Many users deactivate their accounts for temporary reasons and in doing so expect us to maintain their information until they return to Hot or Not. You will therefore be able to restore your account and your profile in its entirety within 30 days of de-activating it. 

After the expiration of 30 days, your account is permanently deleted from Hot or Not. We delete photographs from our servers within 14 days from the expiration of the deactivation period while other information (such as contact history) is deleted by us over a longer timescale, by way of housekeeping on a periodic basis. You should only delete your account if you are certain you never want to restore it. 

To prevent abuse and/or misuse of Hot or Not by a user following termination or deletion of a profile/account we shall retain such information as we deem in our sole discretion may be necessary to ensure that user does not open a new account and profile in breach of our [Terms and Conditions of Use](http://hotornot.com/terms/) and to ensure compliance with all laws and regulations. 

Warning: Even after you remove information from your profile or delete your account, copies of that information may still be viewable and/or accessed on the Internet to the extent such information has been previously shared with others, or copied or stored by other users or to the extent such information has been shared with search engines. We cannot control this, nor do we accept any liability for this. If you have given third party applications or websites access to your personal information they may retain such information to the extent permitted under their terms of service or privacy policies. 

Removed and deleted information may persist in backup copies for up to 30 days to enable restoration, but will not be available to others in the meantime. 

#### What happens if I do nothing? 

If you have not signed in to Hot or Not for three months, we may remove your Profile as part of our data cleansing process. 

Your Hot or Not account is non-transferable and any rights to your profile or contents within your account will be cancelled upon your death. 

If you have questions about our Privacy Policy or how we collect and use information, contact us through our website. 

## Useful links

You might also want to take a look at the following pages:

[Terms and Conditions](http://hotornot.com/terms/): to find out how we govern the relationship between you and Hot or Not.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 8 June 2015.
